69. Magic Realism. Literature is a huge concept. In order to talk about it more
meaningfully, we break it down into styles, groups of writing that use
similar effects, themes, or tactics. One of these styles is magic realism. Magic
realism in literature comes from South America. The Colombian writer Gabriel
Garcia Marquez is one writer very closely associated with the term. But
magic realism was actually first used by a German art critic in 1925 to talk
about a style of painting. That style of painting, putting magical objects or
concepts in a real world, had the same effect as magic realism in literature.
However, magic realism wasn't used as a literary term until 1955. Magic realism
is not fantasy. Instead, it is serious realistic fiction that includes magical
or supernatural elements in a real normal setting. The magical elements in
that setting are not seen as magic. They're just part of a world that looks
like ours but is slightly different. Magic realism uses these magic elements
to help tell very real, not fantastic, stories. In order for magic realism to
work, the reader must accept that these magic elements are not necessarily
surprising but just part of the world of the story. Magic realism is a complicated
idea. Some critics say the term is out-of-date now and want a new, more
accurate one. Some critics have never liked the term and say it contributes to
racism. Instead of letting this type of Latin American writing simply join
literature, a new genre was created to avoid taking it seriously. Magic realism
has played a very important role in modern literature. What it will do in the
future is today's question. Will it continue to tell serious stories or will
it merge with light fiction and fantasy?